Okay.
It is
Very
tire.
It's beautiful.
She would have
Sorry.
I'm tired.
Have you tried
it?
because we were running low on charged
batteries.
Someone's not here to put them charger.
Perfect. Give me
>> Good morning. Good morning.
Welcome to Consumed.
Glad you're here with us today.
We're all about being in a space and
creating the time
for heaven to meet earth.
And heaven is where God's presence is.
Amen.
>> So heaven doesn't have to be far away.
There's at least uh three or four
mountains in the Old Testament referred
to as the mountain of God.
Well, is that a mistake? Is that a
contradiction? No. They just called it
the mountain of God. Whenever God would
show up.
Whatever mountain God was on, that was
the mountain of God. So, we just
proclaim in this place.
This is the space where heaven can come
because his spirit is here with us.
Amen.
Do you believe this morning that the
spirit is still hovering over the waters
and he's bringing order out of chaos?
How many believe that?
So, let's just invite him here. Let's
invite the spirit to blow over us today.
Whatever
torment and violence is in our lives,
whatever chaos is happening,
let's just take a deep breath. Let the
spirit begin to move over us this
morning. Father, we just invite you.
Blow with your Holy Spirit over us this
morning.
Father, we just receive life this
morning that comes from your throne. We
thank you for your dwelling presence
with us. Not just in our hearts but
among us as a people.
So we just speak the presence of the
Lord in this in this place. We receive
it.
We just say, spirit, do your work in us
this morning to make us right and
aligned with you. And all of the
priorities of heaven would become ours.
All of the visions
and thoughts and imaginations of heaven
would become ours this morning.
So let let's just enter into his
presence as he fills this place
and bless his name. Amen.
God,
Father
Jesus Christ.
Calm
down.
Calm down.
I found the power.
Thank you Jesus.
>> Sing praises to your name,
oh Lord.
Praises to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great
and greatly
to be praised.
I sing praises to your name,
oh Lord.
Praises to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly
to be praised.
I sing glory. I sing glory to your name,
oh Lord.
Glory to your name,
oh Lord,
for your name is great and greatly
to be praised.
I sing glory to your name,
oh Lord,
glory to your name,
for your name is great and greatly
to be praised.
I sing glory to your name,
oh Lord,
glory to your name,
for your name is great and greatly
to be praised.
I sing praises to your name,
oh Lord.
Praises to your name,
>> oh Lord,
for your name
is great
and greatly
to be praised.
your name.
For your name is great
and greatly
to be praised.
>> For your name, For your name
is great
and greatly
to be praised.
Jesus.
>> Jesus.
>> No name above your name.
>> Your name's above every other name.
I choose this day
to be grateful, Lord.
I give you praise
with an open heart. I'm waking up to
heaven.
I'm waking up to you.
I choose this day.
I choose this day
to be grateful. Lord,
I give you praise
with an open heart.
I'm waking up to heaven.
I'm waking up to you. I'm waking up.
I'm waking up to you
for always being good.
For always being good.
Thank you
for your mercies that are new.
in spirit and in truth.
Thank you. I'm telling you, thank you.
Your faithfulness,
your faithfulness
is like a sunrise.
Your endless love
reaches past the skies.
I'm waking up to heaven.
I'm waking up to you. Your faithfulness,
your faithfulness,
your faithfulness.
It's like a sunrise.
And let's fly
past the skies.
I'm waking up to the
I'm waking up to you. Wake us up.
I'm waking up to heaven.
I'm waking up to you
for always being good.
For always being good, we say thank you
for your mercies that are new every
morning. Thank you
in spirit and in truth.
Thank you. I'm telling you, thank you
for always being good.
For always being good.
Thank you
for your mercies that are new.
Thank Thank you
in spirit and in truth.
Thank you. I'm telling you. Thank you.
You and you alone.
Awakening up my soul.
And it's my joy to thank you.
Thank you and you alone
awaking up my soul.
And it's my joy to thank you
and thank you and you alone.
The waking up my soul.
It's my joy to thank you.
Thank you and you alone
for waking up our souls.
And it's our joy to thank you. We say
thank you
for always being good.
Thank you
for your mercies that are new.
in spirit and in truth.
Thank you. I'm telling you thank you.
We're telling you thank you.
Tell him thank you.
We're telling you thank you. We've got
so much to be thankful for. I'm telling
you, thank you
for the breath in my lungs.
I'm telling you, thank you.
We're telling you, thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you
for you and you alone.
The waking up my soul.
>> And it's my joy.
It's our joy. It's our joy.
You and you alone.
Waking up my soul.
And it's my joy to thank you.
Thank you for you alone.
>> You're waking up our soul
and it's our joy. Thank you.
Thank you. And you alone
are waking up our souls.
And it's our joy to thank you.
Thank you.
>> We're telling you thank you.
Oh Jesus.
>> That's how we enter
with thanksgiving.
>> Yeah. Come on.
>> That's how we enter
with thanksgiving.
What a joy and a privilege.
It's how we enter.
It's with thanksgiving.
What a joy. What a privilege.
It's how we enter.
It's with thanksgiving.
What a joy. What a privilege.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank
you. Thank you. Thank you. Overflowing.
Oh, we say thank you. Thank you. Thank
you.
Oh, we thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> We thank you. Thank you.
Oh, we thank you. Thank you.
>> We come in with thankful heart. We thank
you. Thank you.
>> Oh, we thank you. Thank you.
>> We thank you.
>> Come on. It's a good thing to posture
our hearts.
We're singing out, "Thank
you.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Heart full of praise.
Heart full of thanks
overflowing.
We say thank you.
Lord, we come in with humble, lowly
hearts, Lord, to
just be in your midst.
What an honor,
Lord. These aren't empty words. This is
a history of thanksgiving.
Lord, we have so much to be thankful
for.
>> There's testimony after testimony in
this room.
We've seen your faithful hand,
>> Lord. We say thank you for being here.
Thank you for delivering us. Thank you
for saving us. Thank you for redeeming
us.
Thank you for washing us clean, God. We
thank you. There's so much to be
thankful for, church.
>> Thank you, God.
Lord, you're worthy of everything.
Worthy of every song we could ever sing.
Worthy of all the praise we could ever
bring.
Worthy of every breath we could ever
breathe. We live for you.
Sing it again. Worthy.
Worthy of every song we could ever sing.
Worthy of all the praise we could ever
breathe.
Worthy of every breath we could ever
breathe. We live for you.
>> Jesus. Sing Jesus the name.
Jesus the name above every other name.
Jesus the only one who could ever sing.
Worthy of every breath we could ever
breathe. We live for you.
Oh, we live for you. Sing holy
and holy.
There is no one like you. There is none
beside you. Open up my eyes in want to.
Show me who you are and fill me with
your heart and lead me in your love to
those. Sing it again. Tell him and holy
there is no one like you. There is none
beside you. Open up my eyes in wonder.
Show me who you are and fill me with
your heart and lead me in your love to
those around
me.
Holy,
holy,
sing
worthy.
Worthy of every song we could ever sing.
Worthy of all the praise we could ever
bring.
Worthy of every breath we could ever
breathe. We live for you.
Oh, we live for you, Jesus.
Jesus, the name above every other name.
Jesus, the only one who could ever save.
Worthy of every breath we could ever
breathe. We live for you.
Yeah. We live for you. Sing holy
and holy.
There is no one like you. There is none
beside you. Open up my eyes.
You show me who you are and fill me with
your heart and lead me in your love to
those. You are holy,
holy.
There is no one like you. There is none
beside you. Open up our eyes in wonder.
Show me who you are and fill me with
your heart and lead
in your love to those around
me.
Won't you lead us?
Won't you lead us? Holy Spirit,
we are the leader. You are the leader.
Oh, we follow the leader.
I will follow you for all my days.
>> Oh, I will follow you for all my days.
I will follow the leader. I am not the
high priest. I am not the high priest
you are.
I thank you God.
Let's sing this out. I will build my
life.
I will build my life upon
your
>> lift it up and I will put my trust in
you.
In I
>> Come on, let's make this a prayer. Come
on, press in. I will
my life
upon
it is
>> you are the firm foundation
put my trust
you are
and I will not
you are holy
holy
There is no one like you. There is none
beside you. Open up my eyes and wonder
and show me who you are and fail me with
your heart and lead me in your love.
You are holy, holy, holy.
There is no one like you. There is none
beside you. Open up my eyes.
Open up and show me who you are and fill
me with your heart and lead me in your
love.
I will build I will build and I will
build my life upon
your love. It is a firm foundation
and I will put my trust in you
and I will not be shen.
>> Oh will not be shen.
We will not be shaken.
>> My firm foundation.
>> We have built our lives on this truth.
>> My solid rock which I stand.
All other ground is shifting sand. All
other ground is sinking sand.
You're my solid rock.
My firm found.
>> Yeah.
>> My firm found.
>> Jesus.
I will build my life. Come on. Let's
pray it.
and I will build my life upon your love.
It is a fat foundation.
And I will put my trust in you alone.
And I will not be shen.
Come on, lift up your own voice.
>> Sing your own melody.
>> Come on, let's stand on this truth for a
little bit.
>> Come on, minister to the king. Minister
to the king, church. Come on.
You don't need us to lead you.
You have your own voice. Tell him,
>> Lord, we will build our lives on this
truth.
>> I build my life on the rock of Jesus.
>> Build my life
upon this truth.
>> For my rock, my firm foundation.
So worthy is the lamb.
>> Seated
on the throne.
>> We crown you now with many
crowns.
You reign
victorious.
us
and highly lifted
up.
Jesus, son of God,
the talling of heaven
crucified.
Worthy is the lamb.
Come on, lift it up. Worthy.
Come on, let's keep singing this. Tell
him, "Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy, worthy,
worthy is the lamb."
One more time. Worthy,
worthy is the lamb.
Worthy, worthy is the lamb.
>> Sing. Worthy is the lamb
and worthy is the lamb. Come on, lift it
up.
See it on the throne.
We crown you now with many
crowns.
You reign victorious
high and lifted up high and lifted
up.
Jesus son of God. Jesus son of God.
The dwelling of heaven
crucified.
Worthy, worthy.
Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy, worthy is the lamb.
Sing it again. Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy, worthy,
worthy is the lamb.
Oh, let's sing it again. Worthy is the
lamb
and worthy is the lamb.
Seated on the throne.
We call you down.
You reign victorious
high.
High and lifted
up.
Jesus.
Jesus. Son
of God.
The darling of heaven
who
worthy is the lamb.
Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy.
>> We give you glory, God.
>> Worthy of praise.
Honor and riches worth.
>> There's none like you.
There's none beside you.
Oh, worthy is the lamb.
Oh, worthy is the Lamb.
Oh, worthy is the Lamb. I want to keep
singing and tell him,
"Oh, worthy is the Lamb."
Worthy is the lamb.
Worthy is the
We love you.
Oh, we love you,
Jesus. We love
you.
Oh, how we love
You are the one.
>> Our hearts to
Jesus we love. love you.
>> Oh, how we love
you.
>> You are the one
I heart to adore.
We love you, God.
How
you love
how we love
how we
I was just in awe of his presence in
this room. I just feel the glory cloud
just kind of swirling around.
I mean, if you're not sensing it, just
lean into his presence. Just focus on
him.
And as we've committed oursel to build
our life on you
and put oursel in that posture, it's you
who are doing the building. Father, we
just submit to your your construction
project in us to heal us, to make us
whole. Father,
>> thank you for your building project in
each one of us. And as you work on each
one,
Father, you're building us into a
community. Father, those lights and
salts in the earth, Father, we glorify
you in this place, Father. All the
titles that we've called you this
morning, they're just loaded. They're
just loaded with meaning.
>> And Father, we just acknowledge the King
in this place. We acknowledge the son of
God.
>> The darling of heaven.
>> We acknowledge the darling of heaven.
>> That son of God. Even the title is has
kingship all loaded in there. Father, we
do crown you. We do crown you with our
lives. You have been crowned. And we
crown you again and again and again. and
every crown that we would hope to
receive, we throw it at your feet,
Father, as the elders are doing right in
this moment, Father. We lay
every achievement in our life before
you, Lord, just as you have taken every
wrong and every destruction. We give you
everything that we've done right,
Father. It's all for you. We humble
ourselves before you and say, "It is all
you. It is all your grace this morning
and we receive from you, Lord. That
completed work that's promised, we
receive it right now. Thank you for your
rescue from darkness. But we know saving
is something that's happening right now.
You are saving us
>> and you will save these bodies in the
resurrection. But I thank you. I thank
you for right now in this moment, how
you're moving and you're saving us.
Thank you, God, for your saving power
that's in your name. You are the one who
saves. Thank you, God.
Let's just receive that saving power
over us right now.
>> Thank you, God.
>> Bless you, Lord.
Jesus.
Oh, how
I know the spirit can continue to work
despite our transitions, but it's
doesn't make it easy.
just let him continue to work in our
hearts.
Well, let's just take a moment to love
on one another,
see the glory of the Lord in each other,
and give thanks for that. Embrace one
another. Amen.
I don't
How are you?
I don't know.
All right. Well, welcome back. I hope
everyone feels thoroughly greeted this
morning.
This is uh one of our highlights.
Catch up and greet one another. If this
is your f first time, I I want to
welcome you here at Consume Church. And
uh there's several ways to connect with
us. Either a card in the back
or we'll put up a QR code there if you
are familiar with technology and can
just fill that out for us. We'd like to
get to know you. Um here at Consumed, uh
we have several ways to give and I just
personally want to thank all of you for
your faithful giving. Um it's just a
blessing to see your generosity and uh
we have an app that's uh called the
church center app is is probably the
easiest way to do it. You can also go to
the website. Scanning the QR code will
get you there directly. And then we have
a traditional box in the back if you
want to do it the oldfashioned way. And
uh we have a new tradition uh here at
Consumed of actually declaring over our
giving that God would use this for the
benefit of the kingdom and all of the
dynamic that goes into our giving of
ourselves to him. So I invite you to
stand.
Let's just read this together.
As we receive today's offering, we call
to mind our covenant membership in the
Messiah. In the world, there is never
enough, but in him, we have no lack. In
the Messiah, we are inheriting all
things. Our generosity is an expression
of our identity as God's children. To be
like our generous father, we give with
good measure, pressed down, shaken
together, and running over. We freely
give not from compulsion, but joyfully
as an act of giving loyalty. We declare
that every part of our life belongs to
him, just as he has given all of himself
to us.
May the sacrifices we give today be a
sweet smelling aroma to diffuse the
fragrance of Christ in every place
through the church to reveal his
kingdom, extend his freedom and impart
new life until every enemy is put under
his feet. Hallelujah. Amen. Amen. Thank
you.
And one of our themes this year is that
Jesus is putting his enemies under his
feet and we're reclaiming ground this
year. And it may not feel that way. Um,
I wasn't going to do this, but Thursday
I was taking advantage of the little bit
cooler weather before the inferno hits
and uh was taking a hike and I was
listening to audio through uh uh Joshua
and it said, "God will go out as a
hornet before you and destroy his
enemies." And right then a hornet
probably three foot three inches long
like this started buzzing right in front
of me and then circled around me several
times. that flew off and I think said,
"Thank you, Lord. Thank you, Lord."
I mean, right that instant when I was
hearing that verse,
>> this hornet showed up. I was like,
"Thank you, God."
>> Yes. So, I don't know if there's omens
or signs or anything like that, but I I
just took it as confirmation that the
Lord is going before us. So, uh, just to
catch you up on some of the activities,
uh, we have our regular Wednesday night
flow service at 6:30 and the youth meet
next door at 6:30 as well. Uh, come join
us, be a part of that. Uh, it's another
opportunity to just drop into what the
spirit is doing and there is no junior
holy spirit. So, we believe the youth
can do that as well. And that's one
thing listening to the Old Testament is
like how things can change in one
generation.
>> Amen.
>> Either for the good or the bad. So let's
let's pray this generation.
>> We see that marked turnaround in them.
We're always speaking to that end. But
uh we've got to be faithful. Even us old
guys, right? Continue the march to the
end. So uh those are the two ones uh
during the week. Uh we also have Friday
night twice a week. It's the first and
third Friday night for the young adults.
So, come join that if you're in that
demographic. Uh we also have a community
impact and I got a couple announcements
about that. So, we've been meeting
second and fourth Saturdays
uh once usually to kind of just rally
together, but the the last Saturday of
the month is usually to actually be in
the community and minister. and we've
been passing out uh groceries
uh to some families in our mobile home
park here locally. So, if you didn't
know that, that's what we've been about.
And we may wind that part of it down for
the summer. We'll see. And and engage in
some other things. But before school
starts here, it's right up on us. We
want to try to kick off this back to
school rally for those families
specifically in that area. We've we've
had brief contact with many of them and
some of them have even more intimate uh
relationship with us and he actually
came to Freedom Reigns. Uh and there's a
lot of families with a bunch of kids.
So just pray about supporting into this.
It's our outreach, right? Our outreach
tab. Uh, so, uh, what I've looked at is
about $80 to give one kid, uh, a good
pack of supplies that are general to all
elementary grades. So, we've done some
of that logistic work. Uh, when we
deliver groceries this next Saturday,
we'll get a final count of how many
families want to do that. Uh, but in the
meantime, you can join us in praying for
that and giving in to that. We sure
would appreciate it.
Amen. Amen. I just want to bless our
community and a real tangible way and
serve them. So, I think that's it for
now. I I want to do a little something a
little bit different. Uh, Pastor John,
come on up.
I just publicly
want to speak a blessing over Pastor
John this morning.
He alone knows all of the behind the
scenes and the challenges this year and
the stuff that he carries.
Let's just uh extend your hands to him
and just speak a blessing over him and
this morning as well, but just in
general. Father, I was just seeing this
morning how you just desire to hold John
in the cliff of the rock and just expose
yourself and shine upon
John this morning and in this season,
Father, and lighten the load that he's
carried. Father, we just bless him as a
shepherd over the over this flock, over
over this people, God, uh to be upheld
like Aaron and hold his arms up in that
rally of what you're doing in this
place. And Father, we just call upon
your strength. We call upon your
endurance on his life and encouragement
over his heart, Lord. So, just bless his
word this morning. Um, bless his mind,
bless his heart, Lord, to communicate
all the things he has for us this
morning in Jesus name. Amen. Amen. Yeah.
Well, thank you all of you for that.
That's very encouraging. And Allan, it's
so wonderful to see you just thriving in
your gifting. And and guys, we
we are so blessed to have Allen's
leadership as he uh is leading out into
uh this community impact initiative to
take that heart of an evangelist and and
to really uh love our neighbors and um
so Allan, thank you for taking
initiative and doing all that stuff. So
um I'm excited about what God's going to
do in and through our church. It seems
like every time we start something
evangelistic or something new, it takes
a little while for people to really buy
in. And is this for real? Is this going
to last? Are these guys just coming up
with something extra for us to do? Are
we really going to make a difference in
the world? And uh I know that Allan
believes in outreach with everything
that is in him from like the fiber of
his being. So otherwise, God bless you
for championing uh that expression of
the body of Christ and out of this
house. So
all right. Well, good morning. It's good
to see you guys. Uh, Pastor Matthew is
visiting family in California. Some of
you know of some of the going on in his
life in the last several months and it's
um just a real blessing and opportunity
for him to be with his family. So, we're
thankful for that and uh father just
keep doing a mighty work in him and in
his family in Jesus name.
So today I was thinking about um how I
have a a visitor, a guest here from
Italy. He was in the room. I don't see
him. But uh it's it's funny how often
we're able to see ourselves through the
eyes of someone else. uh maybe sometimes
more sharply and clearly than we're used
to because uh you know we get familiar
with the way in which we do life but um
having been to Italy and seeing how
things are thousands of years old and
all built out and the culture generally
is much slower paced. It's like things
are already built. You're not changing
those streets. You're not changing those
roads. I how many of you would like for
us to get to a place where our roads are
like done?
>> I know I would. But it's funny to take
them into a a grocery store and you
know, I I think we don't realize how
much different it is here from the rest
of the world.
You know, we say that things that are
bigger in Texas. Everything's bigger in
Texas. But North Texas, we're known for
big stuff, right? Big stores, big
trucks,
big dreams. Yeah. Big big churches,
big highways, and lately big traffic,
big growth. How about this one? Big data
centers. If you y'all even notice that
like what is that massive weird looking
building? It's a data center. Big
expectations,
big cost of living.
Every year more people come here chasing
opportunity. Did you guys realize this
is one of the fastest growing areas in
the whole entire world populationwise?
North Texas is rapidly approaching 9
million people residents.
>> Yep. And with all of that expansion
comes longer commutes, faster
development, and increasing pressure on
daily life. Has anybody I Oh, thank you.
>> Has anybody noticed that?
>> Yes.
>> But here's what I've noticed. Most of us
don't need another opportunity. We need
another hour.
We don't need another promotion. We need
another breath.
>> Have you noticed how we're connected to
everyone and yet truly connected to no
one?
People feel lonier today than ever,
being more connected than ever.
AI systems in their pressure to make
every part of our lives
perfect and more efficient are rapidly
changing the face of how we do
everything.
Am I having trouble here?
>> Sorry, technical difficulties. Let me
try this. How's that?
The standard of excellence and the speed
at which things keep evolving is
dizzying.
It's like everything has changed. If
you're not keeping up with the latest
trends, it's almost like you feel like
you're in a vacuum or in a dark room all
alone. I don't know if you've noticed
that yet, but six months ago, a year
ago, we were talking about AI. What's
this going to do to our world? I think
we're finding out.
In a matter of seconds, we're spitting
out more content than any human could
possibly absorb or consume.
It seems there's no arena of life that
is untouched by this relentless pursuit
of growth and perfection.
The pressure to keep up is real.
This is the kicker. Christians are now
turning to technology and social media
for spiritual formation.
We are it's it's easy just to flip on a
podcast or download a sermon or whatever
on the go.
Opportun while there's opportunities
slow down enough for real disciplehip
have almost completely vanished.
We have built lives with no margin.
Look familiar?
We have filled every margin and then
wonder why we have no room for God,
community or rest. Our culture tells us
to maximize every moment. Work more, buy
more, experience more, scroll more.
But a life, a full life isn't
necessarily a meaningful life.
>> Consumerism tells us we need more.
Social media tells us everyone else is
doing more.
So we keep adding
while losing our peace, our presence,
and our attention.
When life gets too busy,
the life of the church begins to feel
optional.
It's true.
Gathering happens only when nothing else
is scheduled.
I I never thought I would see a time
when that was the case. But it's here,
guys. This is unprecedented times that
we live in. I believe
community has become secondary. Jesus
gets whatever margin remains. And that
margin is getting ever ever so tight and
thin.
So what is margin? We'll talk about
margin.
Margin is the space between our load and
our limits.
It's the white space on a page.
It's the shoulder on the highway.
It's the emergency fund in your budget,
the buffer in your calendar.
Get this. Without margin, every
inconvenience becomes a crisis.
You ever feel that way?
overreacting to things.
Without margin, every interruption
becomes an irritation.
Don't have time for that right now.
Without margin, every delay becomes
anger.
Without margin, every needy person
becomes an obstacle.
So, the problem isn't that we're busy.
Jesus was busy. He was always busy.
problem is we're busy without
boundaries.
>> Gonna
refer to John Mark Comr. G he he says
Jesus was never in a hurry.
One of the strangest things about Jesus
is how unhurried he is.
Think about it. People are dying.
Crowds are waiting. Demons are
screaming. Religious leaders are
plotting murder. And Jesus, he just
walks.
He stops for children.
He notices birds.
He attends weddings.
He takes naps.
Glory to God. Can I get an amen?
He disappears to lonely places to be
with the father.
John Mark Comr says this, "Hurry isn't
merely an external pace.
It reshapes the kind of people we
become."
I know.
I used to be the efficiency king. Some
folks that work for me, they'll tell
you, you get that guy on the tools and
he's a different person.
Look out.
The gospels reveal that Jesus refuses to
let urgency become his master.
Jesus had enough margins to notice
Zakius.
He had enough margin to bless children.
He had enough margin to stop for a
bleeding woman while a little girl had
died
and he was about to raise her from the
dead.
Love requires margin.
We cannot love at highway speed.
>> So
in this day and age, in this culture,
guys, this is for real. I get it. I
mean, I'm a part of it. I feel it. What
are the people of God to do? Surely,
this can't be the way that this turns
out. That the church just dries up.
There are other countries where there
are empty church buildings everywhere
for decades. Nobody in them. That's
starting to happen here in America.
Churches are closing like crazy.
But this problem isn't a new problem.
This is an ancient problem. We may have
new technology and new challenges, but
it's the same spirits that we face. And
God has always had an answer. Anyone
want to guess?
Sabbath.
>> What are we doing about Sabbath?
You got to know I'm preaching to me more
than anybody.
>> Reading my own mail.
Let's look at some scripture.
Uh, Exodus 20
verse 8.
Read the underlines with me.
Remember the Sabbath day. By the way,
we're jumping in the middle of the ten
commandments. Remember the Sabbath day
to keep it holy.
Six days you shall labor and do all your
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord your God. In it you shall do
no work. You nor your son, nor your
daughter, nor your male servant, nor
your female servant, nor your cattle,
nor your stranger who is within your
gates. For in six days the Lord made the
heavens and the earth, the sea, and all
that is in them, and rested the seventh
day. Therefore, the Lord blessed the
Sabbath day and hallowed it.
I'm going to admit that the Sabbath is
often misunderstood. I think it has been
for probably centuries.
But Sabbath was never about a rule. It
wasn't just a religious practice.
It was not even just about rest. It's
about identity.
It's about who they were as the people
of God.
as we see in that first
uh example of the ten commandments and
then over and over and over again in
Leviticus and Deuteronomy as well as
Exodus,
the Lord explains this as a reminder
that they belonged to the one true God,
the creator God who himself rested on
the seventh day. was a way for them to
identify themselves, to be a part of the
covenant, to be a part
of God himself. His special people meant
that they emulated God, that God himself
rested, that's why they rested.
We're going to do a little bit of a dive
on the Sabbath here. Is everybody okay
with that?
>> It's been a while. I don't know that
I've spoke on this in a while. Maybe
never. I don't know.
identity. It was a way for the people of
God to be like God in their work,
in their vocation,
their purpose in the earth.
The commandment is not just that the
Israelites themselves
were taking a break for the sake of
taking a break,
but that those among them, their
servants, their children, the stranger,
the foreigners, the animals, all of them
experienced God's generous heart
through them as a people
to have leadership over them that was
good to them.
and not a slave driver like what they'd
experienced in Egypt to set a holy
example
to testify of who God is by
his people exercising grace.
I've never looked at it like this
before. Sabbath was observed as a sign
of who they were as the people of God.
Let's look at Exodus 31.
He says quite clearly right here, "Speak
also to the children of Israel, saying,
Surely my Sabbath you shall keep,
for it is a sign
between me and you throughout your
generations, that you may know that I am
the Lord who sanctifies you." So this is
bigger than just getting a break or some
random rule because you need a nap. It's
a bigger thing than that. answer. It's I
am going to identify forever. You will
stand out in the earth throughout all
generations as my people to reflect my
nature and my character as not a slave
driver
but one who gives rest and promises
rest.
Now this for them was a radical shift in
thinking.
Think about it. going from being slaves
under hard labor,
no identity, no value, only what they
could produce
to becoming godlike stewards of creation
to act like God himself
who in the words of Jesus gives rest.
Let's look at some New Testament.
Matthew 11
starting in verse 25.
I apologize for cramming so much on one
page. It's an object lesson in margin.
It's not comfortable to read, right?
Matthew 11:25-30.
At that time, Jesus turned to God with
this prayer. I I put so much on here
because we always jump straight to the
take my yoke upon you. My burden is
light. But it's connected to this
statement that he makes here about
identity
and about God's personality, God's
character. At that time, Jesus turned to
God with his prayer. I give you my
praise. Everybody say it. Father,
>> master of heaven and earth. Master of
heaven and earth. Master is a term for
boss. Father. So, we have a boss. Jesus
is identifying his boss, his leader, the
one in charge of his vocation as a
father,
master of heaven and earth. You hid
these things from the wise and
intelligent and what? Revealed them to
children.
Meaning that it is hard in a employee
employer relationship
to ascertain and to see who God is
without understanding this element of
being a part of the family of having a
loving father.
Yes, father. That's the way you decided
to do it. My father gave me everything.
Nobody knows the son except the father.
And nobody knows the father except the
son and anyone the son wants to reveal
him to. Now, let me just say something
about that for a minute because as a
business owner and as a pastor, in many
ways,
I hope that I exude the heart of the
father, but in many ways, people might
know me in the way that they know me
based on a business relationship, but my
children and those that walk with me
closely know that I'm maybe a little bit
different in the way in which I relate
to people. I hope. Lord, help me.
There's something very special that
Jesus is saying here about our vocation
and our purpose and our work that is
connected to this idea of rest is
knowing God as a really good boss as a
dad. All right. Are you having a real
struggle?
Come to me. Are you carrying a big load
on your back? Come to me.
I'll give you a rest. Pick up my yoke
and take it on.
take lessons from me, I'll be gentle
with you. Jesus is talking about his
work. Often when we preach this, we talk
about taking a nap or something, but
Jesus is actually talking about the way
in which we approach our vocation, our
purpose, our destiny in God, the way in
which we exist to find meaning in the
things that we do. Pick up my yoke and
take it on. Take lessons from me. I'll
be gentle with you. The last thing in my
heart is to give you a hard time. You'll
see. Rest you need and rest you shall
have. It almost sounds like the Yoda
version or something, but my yoke is
easy to wear and my load is easy to
bear. This is the Kingdom Translation,
Kingdom New Testament. I love it. So, we
see that Jesus is emulating and showing
us the Father. This is what he's saying.
I'm showing you the Father. He's gentle
and humble as a boss. He's not the kind
of master that is driving us hard to
judging every mistake,
never giving us a break.
He doesn't overload his employees. He
carries it alongside of us.
Jesus is revealing this heart of the
father in love and compassion
especially in our vocation so that all
may delight in the work of their hands
just like the father did.
I I'd have to say that
for the last decade or so, my
understanding of maybe even longer of
the Sabbath was kind of grounded in
Jesus's approach to the Sabbath seemed
to be not nonchalant, but almost against
the Sabbath. He was constantly doing
things that people wanted to kill him
for because he wasn't practicing the
Sabbath. He would heal on the Sabbath.
He made statements about being the Lord
of the Sabbath.
He seemed like he was disregarding it
and blowing it up, but he was actually
defining the Sabbath.
I want to read a story here in Mark
chapter 2 where we see that Jesus
actually gets angry at the hardness of
the hearts of the Pharisees
because of the irony of them judging him
for breaking the Sabbath and them not
even understanding what it's about.
Let's look at Mark 2.
Lots of scripture today
again from the
Kingdom New Testament.
One Sabbath Jesus is walking through the
corn fields. His disciples made their
way along plucking corn as they went.
"Look here," said the Pharisees to him,
"why are they doing something illegal on
the Sabbath?" "Haven't you read what
David did?" replied Jesus. when he was
in difficulties and he and his men got
hungry, he went into God's house. Uh
this is when Abiar was high priest and
ate the bread of the presence which only
the priests were allowed to eat.
Read the underline. And he gave it to
the people with him. The Sabbath was
made for humans, he said, not humans for
the Sabbath. So the son of man is master
even of the Sabbath. News about him
spread swiftly throughout the entire
region of Galilee.
What verse is that?
Oh, we're going right into chapter
three. Sorry.
Chapter three. Because verse 28 is the
last verse of the chapter. Chapter 3.
Once more Jesus went to the synagogue.
There was a man there with a withered
hand. People were watching to see if
Jesus would heal him on the Sabbath so
that they could frame a charge against
him. Stand up, said Jesus, to the man
with the withered hand and come out
here. And he said to them, looking over
to the Pharisees, "Is it lawful to do
good on the Sabbath or to do evil, to
save life or to kill?" talk about
reading your mail because their whole
point in being a part of this
conversation was they were looking to
kill him.
They stayed quiet. He was deeply upset
at their hard-heartedness. And he looked
round at them angrily. Then he said to
the man, "Stretch out your hand." He
stretched it out and his hand was
restored.
>> Hallelujah. The Pharisees went out right
away and began to plot with the
Herodians against Jesus,
trying to find a way to destroy him.
We see here that the Sabbath is given to
facilitate a healthy stewardship of
creation.
It's a way for the people of God and
really all humanity to look back and be
thankful for the way in which God was
working together with them to create, to
develop, to bless one another, to bless
God,
to reflect and see God at work in the
productivity and creativity that we
exhibited throughout the week.
What I mean, talk about a a shift in
perspective.
What would it be like for us instead of
feeling like we're trying to catch up
all the time, be at a place where
we have a full stop
and turn around and enjoy everything
that God's done.
Celebrate it. I mean, that's what we're
supposed to be doing.
This practicing the rest of God actually
stands in stark contrast to a world that
can never get enough.
The world is always focused on what is
lacking, always dissatisfied,
constantly searching for meaning,
protection, and self-preservation.
Guys, that we don't have to worry about
that stuff.
I I think what happens for us as
believers is we start to get caught up
in the flow of the culture because it it
does it impacts
almost everything. gas pump,
price of groceries,
just staying keeping your business
afloat.
God's people have been set apart,
redeemed to be a whole different
species. Did you know that you're a new
type of human being
identified in Jesus himself, defined in
Jesus,
the God type of human?
By giving us the Holy Spirit, he's given
us the ability to be fully yolked with
him.
Get this one. When we overwork, we
express an unhealthy desire to be
little g godlike
instead of being like God as he has
revealed himself.
So God rests on the seventh day, not
because he's exhausted,
but because he takes up his rest.
God isn't tired. He isn't plopping down
on the couch, throwing up his hands,
can't do anymore.
No, he's beginning to rain. He takes up
his rest. He's beginning to rain from
his completed creation, from a sense of
his good.
It's not God giving up or taking a
break. It's God saying, "It's finished.
Now, let's enjoy what I've made."
So, Tim Mackey points out that Sabbath
is actually woven into the very fabric
of creation before it becomes a part of
Israel's law. The rhythm, I'm sorry, the
rhythm becomes the command, which means
humans were created not just to produce,
but to delight.
>> I I remember there was a
a season in my life where I had um
never made so much money and lived so
little.
I I can't believe it, but I I got caught
up in a company had bought the company
that I worked at and my rhythm got all
messed up and uh they would hand you a a
list every week and say, "You have to
get this list done. We don't care how
you do it." Well, it seemed like because
of their system, it was next to
impossible. And it it wound up being a
situation where everybody was up there
working till 10 o'clock at night, at
least two weeks, the last two weeks of
the month, trying to get the quota. But
I noticed that we started working
Saturdays and then we started working
Sundays, trying to keep up with this
never-ending list of stuff. And I made a
little bit more money. I'm talking like
maybe 5% more money, but I had like 2%
of the life I used to have. I remember
we went we went camping, which is what
we used to do once a month back in those
days when we were raising the kids. I I
went camping. That that was our time to
kick back and
just look at the fruit of our labors and
say, "Wow, you know, we earned a little
time off, three-day weekend or
whatever."
And um I remember going and I was so
tired. All I did is slept in the camper.
Boat sat outside the camper. Didn't do a
thing. Seriously, I thought
I have no energy for anything. Anything
other than keeping up with that hamster
wheel.
So Sabbath is not just about identity.
It's about resistance.
Entright points it out like this. He
says, "For Jews in Jesus's world, the
Sabbath was a badge of Jewishness for
people who'd been persecuted and killed
just for being Jewish.
It was a national flag that spoke of
freedom to come,
of hope for the great day of rest
that was promised by God when he would
finally liberate Israel from pagan
oppression.
It looked back to the creation of the
world to the Exodus and it marked out
those people
who kept it as God's special people, his
faithful people, his loving people, his
hoping people.
The whole point of the commandment was
celebrating God's creation, his
redemption,
both past, present, and future.
That's a pretty big deal because we talk
about our own hope. The promises of
scripture is that Jesus will return and
everything that is heavy will be no
more.
We will be liberated from bondage and
from slavery and we will actually
set all of creation free and the power
and presence the spirit of God will be
everywhere.
>> It's what we're waiting for.
Lately, I've been uh talking about some
perspectives from eaten bar.
As you can imagine, he has some things
to say about the Sabbath.
But he was saying that it's not simply a
Jewish custom. It was Israel's
declaration that Pharaoh no longer owned
them.
For 400 years, their value came from
bricks, quota, output, production.
Sound familiar?
Today, our pharaoh does not carry a
whip. He sends notifications,
>> measures productivity,
rewards availability.
>> He whispers, "You are what you
accomplish."
>> Listen, every time you refuse to stop,
you're declaring that Pharaoh still has
authority.
So every Sabbath is an act of holy
rebellion,
resistance.
Exodus 20.
And God spoke all these words, saying, I
am the Lord your God, who brought you
out of the land of Egypt, out of the
house of bondage. You shall have no
other gods before me. You shall not make
for yourself a carved image, for I, the
Lord your God, am a jealous God. Now, I
cut a little bit of it out. You probably
know that uh verse seven says, you shall
not take the name of the Lord your God
in vain. There's this passion in the
Lord's heart about, hey, I've married
you guys. Like, I've made myself part of
you and you part of me. There is a
special thing that God has done, decided
to do with his people. Not to reign from
above, dictate down here. No, to come
and be present in our midst, to be a
participant in what's going on in the
earth.
And as he's done this,
he's revealed himself in his goodness
and his faithfulness and his loving
kindness and his mercies that never
cease.
And of course, this is the beginning of
the Ten Commandments,
but often it's not so much a bunch of
dos and don'ts without us seeing the
heart of God in here. He does not want
to be associated with gods of Egypt. You
shall have no other god before me.
Before me, that's doesn't register with
us. We think, okay, well, let's not put
idols in here. Well, yeah, that's yeah,
that's true. But he doesn't want to
compete with some other thing ruling
your life.
It was a a little bit more blatant and
obvious in that day because there was
the cultures around them had
other gods. They were very in touch with
their other gods. But their other gods
character and their
forms of worship were very dehumanizing,
very cold, very hard,
brutal,
oppressing.
To me, the commandments reveal a hard
reset in the heart and mind of the
people of God
to discern the character and nature of
God as opposed to any other God.
These relational dynamics reveal a sharp
contrast between who he is and who they
are.
talking about difference. Let's look at
Exodus 23.
Six days you shall do your work, and on
the seventh day you shall rest, that
your ox and your donkey may rest, and
the son of your female servant and the
stranger may be refreshed. And in all
that I have said to you, this is a
kicker, be circumspect and make no
mention of the name of other gods, nor
let it be heard from your mouth.
So much of what we see is just hard and
fast rules is the Lord being like, I'm
not going to share you with some other
god that is trying to destroy you. I've
gone through all this effort to deliver
you and to make you this special
wonderful people.
I don't know. It seems like
seems like today we've lost touch with
the essence of the Ten Commandments. I
don't even know that they're honored
like they used to be. I think they're
bringing them back like in Oklahoma, but
when I was a kid, the Ten Commandments
were on the wall in every public school.
It's just a normal normal thing.
Churches would have them up or whatever.
I think in and even in a lot of
popularized preaching, we kind of do
this law versus grace thing and it's a
easy way to kind of ignore the Ten
Commandments. But the ten commandments,
if we're seeing the heart and mind of
God in them, it's just his like left
story of how to work together,
how to live together.
You see, this
desire of God's heart, don't even talk
about those other gods. So much of what
we are shocked at in the Old Testament
has everything to do
with this idolatry and with other gods.
There's this
war for this middle earth, if I could
use that term, this second heaven. I've
heard people use that term. uh not the
heaven where God reigns, but this space
in the spirit that seems to interfere
with what we do on earth and affect and
influence the things that we do
that has plagued
us from like Genesis 6 on
and uh God's saying, I am going to make
a special people and set you apart and
make you holy and make you part of
myself. And now he's like fully and
totally done that by breathing the life
of the spirit into us. Aren't you
thankful?
>> So there's a difference between getting
ahead
and being ahead
in our work.
sounded clever when I wrote it, but
there's a difference between getting
ahead or trying to get ahead and
actually being the head in our work.
I I remember working for the man for
like 20 years. And somewhere in the
middle of there, I had no idea that what
I was learning how to do was to serve
well. Not just serve the man, but serve
everyone around me.
God changed me completely changed who I
am
in that season.
I I think that there's something that
God is working into the heart of all of
us to learn how to lead from a place of
humility and gentleness
so that we can reflect
his nature, his character to the rest of
the world, to one another but to the
rest of the world. This is the point of
us taking up rest
is so that others will be able to see
who God really is. Am I making sense?
Margin also reveals who we trust. So
here's the uncomfortable question.
Why don't we slow down?
We often say, "I'm too busy. I don't
have time to fill in the blank.
But maybe that's not really true.
Maybe we're too afraid.
Afraid we'll fall behind.
Afraid someone else will get ahead.
I used to be bad about this. I'd get on
the road and, you know, go, "Don't you
pass me."
I can't believe how delivered I am from
that these days. You know, it's because
I'm older or something. Unless I'm
having a bad day.
Are we afraid that business will suffer?
I remember becoming a highly efficient,
highly effective machine at work.
And if I'm being honest, some of that
motivation was just like,
I don't know if God's going to quite
handle this, but I'll work with him to
make sure that we don't get behind,
get a little extra.
I'll let God sort that out, but I'm I
remember feeling that feeling.
Maybe we're afraid the kids won't make
the team or that we won't be able to
give them everything that we didn't ever
get.
Kids can be a powerful and discovering
grandkids can be a powerful motivator to
do things that put you in a bind.
Maybe we're afraid that our future
depends entirely on us.
And Sabbath asks one terrifying
question. Do we really think
that he's not able
to take care of our needs,
to sustain us,
and to redefine us as his people?
That's really, guys, I mean, it's where
the rubber hits the road. And like I
said, I'm preaching to me more than to
anyone else probably.
So why do we need margin?
Oh my gosh. Some of us have built lives
that would really impress Pharaoh. Move
you right up to the top in the slave
list.
We leave before sunrise.
We fight traffic.
Answer emails in the pickup line. Listen
to podcasts at one and a half speed.
Watch Netflix while checking Slack.
Pray while folding laundry.
I've had seasons where the commute. That
was my prayer time. It's not wrong. It's
good. Get it where you can. And wonder
why you can't hear God's voice, though.
I don't think it's because God's
speaking less. How many of you know
God's always speaking?
But a repeated thing I I hear is people
like, "Man, I'm not sure. I haven't
heard the Lord's voice in a long time."
I don't think it's because he's speaking
less. It's probably because we've got
more noise going on than ever.
>> Silence isn't empty. It's often where we
hear God speak.
>> You need some.
>> I miss our condo.
I used to have a place at the lake and
it was so quiet out there.
I could hear the synapses in my brain
firing.
The enemy loves hurry.
Prosperity isn't wrong. It's not evil.
Technology isn't evil. Ambition's not
wrong or evil.
But anything that leaves no room for
God, for your spouse, for your children,
for your neighbors, or even your own
soul becomes
spiritually dangerous.
Satan doesn't always tempt us to sin. He
doesn't have to. Sometimes he's just
trying to wear us out,
distract us from our purpose and our
calling.
So, as we looked at Jesus's invitation
to remind us of that invitation in
Matthew 11, come to me.
Come to me all who are weary.
Notice what he doesn't say. He doesn't
say,
"Come to me who are weary and I'll give
you better time management."
He doesn't offer life hacks.
He offers himself.
his life, his vocation. He's offering us
a job
himself as your boss.
You're like, John, you always talk about
this. Well, maybe it's not always easy
to hear.
Jesus is offering us employment in the
family of God.
I think when we begin to understand and
embrace the offer that he's extending to
us, we're going to discover that he's
the best boss ever.
There, you know, the place I worked at
for 20 years where I'd gotten highly
efficient was awesome. It was God. His
hand was on it. But when he finally
said, "Hey, it's time to go." And I
thought, Lord, I'm making more money
than I've ever made. This can't be God.
And I told Lauren and she said, "Oh,
yeah, it's the Lord." I thought, "Oh,
no. It's God."
It took me a year. I was so caught up in
in my cycle. It was so had become so a
part of who I was. I just couldn't quite
swallow it. That was a hard year.
I knew it was the Lord, but I just
couldn't couldn't get bring myself to
I told this to Duncan Smith once. He
said, 'Are you always that slow to obey
the Lord?
Are you always that disobedient? Maybe
that was how he said it.
Not anymore. I learned my lesson. But I
did not realize how much of my value,
how much of my personality, how much of
who I was was tied up. And really the
person that I had developed that was
this super efficient machine-like
ultimate I was a automotive technician.
Didn't realize how h how much value and
worth I derived from
hey everybody knows that you got a
problem with your car and you don't go
anywhere because this guy's going to
take care of it and fast.
I remember when the Lord said, "It's
time to go." And I finally left. Y'all
have heard me talk about this, but it
was like somebody cut all my wires. I I
mean, internally, I I thought I was
going to freak out. I thought, "I don't
even know how to feel, how to think, how
to be, and the Lord was just like, I've
got you." I remember driving to we had
rented a little building for our first
business. Didn't even know what I was
doing. I was just following the voice of
God. driving there just crying my eyes
out because I said you're killing me.
You're literally killing me right now.
He was I mean who I thought I was. He
was murdering. I had no idea. Dropped me
down in this little boat dealership
where all the guys sit around and talk
about fish. And inside I'm flipping out.
I'm like we production needs to happen
like right now. Like how how is
everybody just like well I guess we'll
get to that tomorrow or Thursday.
And the Lord was like, "Yep, this is
your life now." I thought, "No,
I'm going to die." I got to be honest
with you, you know, as you guys get used
to me as your pastor. I still have a
wiring inside of me that will get with
it. I can get with it.
But I'm so thankful that that's not my
personality. That's not the strongest
part of my personality. I discovered I
couldn't believe it. God was so good to
me.
Couldn't believe it.
I discovered I thought, "Oh, no.
Everything's going to get behind." Oh,
no. I discovered we didn't miss
anything. Never missed a bill. I
remember with fear and trembling going,
"God, okay, I trust you, but I don't
know what I'm going to do." I said, "I
guess I'm going to have to give up all
the things." And I mean, we live below
our means. This is margin, right? We had
lived below our means for a long time,
but for some reason, I still felt like I
had to do all this extra. And the Lord
specifically said, "Your quality of life
will not change one bit."
All I could do is just trust him.
I'm not telling you guys to go quit your
job. I know it's tempting.
Work is not evil. God created us for
work. It's our approach to work that God
is trying to break off of us. Y'all
understand what I'm saying?
>> The deepest margin won't be found in
your planner. It'll be found in his
presence with his people in community
working for his purposes.
That's what God was giving me. He was
breaking me and giving me the ability to
have lots of margin to do the stuff that
he called me to do.
This
So let's get practical
right now in this day and age in this
location. The fastest growing place on
the planet I believe. How are we going
to adjust
to the break neck speed at which the
goalpost keeps moving?
It's hard just to live here.
I remember having friends 15 years ago
that had to move to Oklahoma
just to be able to afford to pay rent.
I am figuring this out, too. I I'm just
going to be honest. As a pastor, there
were seasons in our life where where
Lauren had just said, "Hey, here's your
boundaries. Say no to moving people.
It's a hard no. You're not moving
anybody. You can't get hurt. But I
remember having created like boundaries
in in life. There were seasons in my
life where I did that well. And even now
in ministry, I I'm trying to figure it
out, too. I mean, I'm walking through
this with you guys in our culture and
trying to figure out what does it look
like. So, please don't hear any judgment
in me. I'm inviting us. I believe God is
inviting us all to take a look at where
we're at and say, "You know what? Some
things never change." Like God's
invitation for us to
time out, spend time with me, spend time
with my family. Redirect your whole
entire wiring about why you do the
things that you do. Amen.
So, how about if this week we did
something like go a whole day without
your phone? Can you even remember the
last time you went a day without your
cell phone? Full-on panic mode.
Happened to me last year in Italy. That
was not a good place to be without my
phone.
Didn't speak the language.
How about eating a meal slowly?
Maybe for you it looks like sitting down
with your family and having a meal like
we used to.
That's not traditional. That's like
holy.
It's sacred time.
Speaking of which, can we have the
elements? Let's Let's have a holy meal
together. What do you say?
How about walking around without
earbuds? Does anybody do this?
We're just pumping in podcasts, maybe
jokes, I don't know, the latest
commentary on how to be cool. I'm young.
I'm old, so that doesn't apply to me too
much. But I've noticed for young people,
they watch and listen to all this ways
in which they're training themselves to
be cool, you know, to stay relevant with
the culture.
So for you young people, maybe a day
with no earbuds.
How about if we
read scripture or read something about
scripture without multitasking?
Or if this is just, hey, you know what?
I'm spending time in the word of God
today. Get up early. You can't sleep
anyways. You're too stressed out.
Just go on ahead and get up and read the
word. Spend some time talking to the
Lord. How about saying no to something
good?
Something good that you know you really
don't have time for. This is me.
I say no to you. Please know that I love
you. I'm not going to say no to you. But
say no to something good so you can say
yes to someone better,
namely the Lord.
This this I think is the way that we can
practice the Sabbath without being
legalistic
because the last thing we want to do is
what the Pharisees did and begin to take
that sign of the covenant and turn it
into a sign for something else. Snobby
people, rude people,
nationalistic people,
thankful for America. That's not what
I'm saying. But it can become a badge of
something that other than God's
personality himself.
Can we practice the Sabbath as trust and
identity,
not just some kind of rule, but like
this is who I am. This is an indicator
that goes against the culture. This is
who we are as the people of God.
I don't know. To me, that's a little
different than I've ever seen it.
Practice the Sabbath as part of your
vocation.
Part of this greater hope and
expectation that we're declaring that
God will give us the rest that he's
promised.
The future world that he's promised us
is coming.
And we are taking time out.
We don't care what the world thinks
because we're celebrating that reality.
You guys, if you look like in in the
book of Leviticus, I didn't have it in
here, but I'm thinking somewhere around
20,
there's this promise. If you will keep
the Sabbath, your land will flourish,
your animals will increase in number.
You'll have peace. The sword won't come
against you. You won't even have to look
over your shoulder.
you'll be at rest.
There's something about the way that God
designed this to work that flows with
all of creation. It's only when we start
practicing the ways of the other gods
that we get ourselves into these jams.
Yeah. I'm asking you to
go against the grain, against the
culture. Who's with me?
Well, let's have this meal together.
So Jesus, we thank you for your body.
Lord, we so identify with your flesh
that our bodies
are also union unified with your body.
Lord, the way we spend our time, the
places that we go,
we just surrender to embodying you. Take
the bread with me.
And Lord, we thank you.
We thank you that you have
loaded history
and given us a way for us to remember.
You said to do this in remembrance of
you.
We thank you for this cup, Lord. We
thank you that we all drink into this
cup which is your life,
Lord. We step back into covenant, not
legalism at all, Lord. And I thank you
that your life is not burdensome. It's
not heavy.
Lord, we bring to you in this moment all
of our weariness,
our toil and our exhaustion, our anxiety
and our stress.
We just release it. We let go.
We thank you, God, that you have washed
us in your blood. Take the cup with me.
So Lord, as we go, we just offer up our
lives. God, we pray that throughout this
week and over the next month and year
that we hear the voice of the spirit
calling us to rest, to step into our
identity,
to understand our purpose in you,
Lord. Thank you. What what an honor it
is to be called your children.
Hallelujah.
If you've been watching online, God
bless you.
Thank you for joining us.
Thank you guys for listening.
Now you know, now you can hold me
accountable.
How's pastor getting rest?
Love you guys. If we can agree with you
in prayer, if there's sickness in your
body, if you're struggling in your
finances or if this message has shaken
you up and irritated you in any way,
please
call me. Set set an appointment. We'll
go to lunch. We'll talk about it.
Bless y'all.
Thank you.